Peter Neagoe Papers
Peter Neagoe Papers
- Writings
  - Short stories
    - French translations of stories by Lucienne Escoube (Box 12)
      L' Oncle Gherasim, translated by Mathilde Cambi
    - Gavrila's Confession, printed pages, with last page typed manuscript (Box 12)
    - Genius, longhand original and typescript draft (Box 12)
    - The Gift of the Star (Box 12)
    - A Gypsy and His Bear (Box 12)
    - Haste Makes… (Box 12)
    - The Heart Has its Own Reasons, alternate title: "Ask Not the Heart" (Box 12)
    - The Hermit's Grace (Box 12)
    - Hey-Day (Box 13)
    - His is the Kingdom (Box 13)
      See also material filed under alternate title, Blossoming World.
    - The Home (Box 13)
    - The Home Remedy (Box 13)
    - Horoscope (Box 13)
    - Josephine (Box 13)
    - Joseph's Bargain (Box 13)
    - The Lamb and the Wolves (Box 13)
    - Light in the Darkness, longhand original and typescript drafts; two copies marked in pencil "for a play", another one marked as "project for novel" (Box 13)
    - Little Marie the Goosegirl (Box 13)
    - Long Live Life, longhand original and typescript draft (Box 13)
    - A Loose Tongue, longhand original and typescript draft (Box 13)
    - Lupu the Haiduc (Box 13)
    - Man Must Choose (Box 13)
    - Mariana (Box 13)
    - The Minstrel of Arles (Box 13)
    - The Miracle (Box 13)
    - El Monte de los Olivos, in Spanish; unclear whether Neagoe wrote this, because there is nothing else written in Spanish in his writings (Box 13)
    - Mr. Warren, longhand original (Box 13)
    - The Noble End (Box 13)
    - Not Too Much to Ask (Box 13)
    - A Novelists Survey of the Arts (Box 13)
    - Ochi, in Romanian (Box 13)
    - Of Man and Beasts (Box 13)
    - Old Bill Carver (Box 14)
    - Old John (Box 14)
    - The Old Oak, includes facsimile of payment check to Neagoe signed by well-wishers (Box 14)
    - Omicron and Omega (Box 14)
    - On the Jewish God, short, only 1 page (Box 14)
    - On the Squares of Paris, alternate title: "The Strong Men of Marseille" (Box 14)
    - On the Word (Box 14)
    - One Care (Box 14)
    - The Orange (Box 14)
    - Orchids for Mr. Smith (Box 14)
    - Paris Projections (Box 14)
    - Pere Dumas (Box 14)
    - Peter the Great (Box 14)
    - The Play of Destiny (Box 14)
    - The Rivals (Box 14)
    - The Rooster Who Outwitted the Fox, includes signed letter outlining book sale proceeds (Box 14)
    - Sculpture (Box 14)
    - The Sea, includes clipping of a short prose piece by Negoe entitled "Joy of Life" (Box 14)
    - The Seed (Box 14)
    - A Simple Case (Box 14)
    - Soul and Soil (Box 14)
    - Spring (Box 14)
    - Stefan, the Miracle Man (Box 14)
    - Story (Box 14)
    - Strange Provision, alternate title: "Monsieur de Paris" (Box 14)
    - Surreality (Box 15)
    - There are No More Tomorrows (Box 15)
    - There is No Paradise, alternate title: The Sculptor" (Box 15)
    - Three After Anyone (Box 15)
    - Till Death Do Us Part (Box 15)
    - Tom Stark's Wisdom (Box 15)
    - The Troubadour (Box 15)
    - Twice Lucky (Box 15)
    - Two Lessons in One (Box 15)
    - Unto Your Children's Children, alternate title (crossed-out): "Bitter Fruit" (Box 15)
    - Victims (Box 15)
    - The Village, longhand original and typescript drafts; more an undeveloped story idea than actual short story (Box 15)
    - Wax and Flames (Box 15)
    - We Bought a House (Box 15)
    - Where There is Smoke (Box 15)
    - Who Conquers Himself (Box 15)
    - The Wisdom of Dr. DeCasaros (Box 15)
    - The Wonder Worker (Box 15)
    - You Know as Well as I (Box 15)
  - Speeches
    - Miscellaneous, 1934; 1936,; 1944,; undated (Box 15)
      Speech May 10th, 1934 - buff paper 5 pp. typescripts
      About Language (Y.M.C.A.) Sun. March. 15, 1936 - 7 pp. white type
      Martha Dean Program April 10, 1936 - 7 pp. white type
      World Peaceways Talk March 19, 1944 - 3 pp. white type
      Trends in Modern Literature, undated - 17 pp.
      Elements of Time & Memory in Literature - lecture, Mar 30 [no year given], 3 pp. white typescript
  - Miscellaneous
    - Artist biographies, longhand and typescript, in English and French; includes Paul Cezanne, Edgar Degas, Paul Ganguin, Claude Monet, Auguste Renoir, and Vincent Van Gogh; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Epigrams (Box 15)
    - Notes, nearly all in longhand; titles given are those on original folders
      - "Ideas - Notes - Misc.", 2 folders (Box 16)
      - "Ideas to be looked over P.N." (Box 16)
      - "Items to be looked over - Misc. Notes" (Box 16)
      - "Notes for stories" - Longhand and typescript (Box 16)
      - "Notes-Ideas-Misc", typescript pieces (Box 16)
      - "Notes - Ideas - Misc. P.N.", 2 folders (Box 16)
      - "Notes to be Examined", 2 folders (Box 16)
      - "Notes to be Examined", 2 folders (Box 17)
      - "Original notes" (Box 17)
      - [Untitled], 3 folders (Box 17)
    - "What is Surrealism", discussion of Peter's 1932 booklet of the same name (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous fragments (Box 17)
- Miscellaneous
  - Photocopies of collection material, unclear why these were copied or by who and for what purpose; all are stamped "photocopied from original manuscript in Syracuse University Library" (Box 17)
  - Preface to From a Paris Garret by Richard le Gallienne, photocopy (Box 17)